More Minetyst work

Day 00124: Thursday, 2015 July 09

PayPal hasn't written back about the donation on behalf of the website yet.

The first minetest_game module I started work on converting today was screwdriver. It seemed pretty easy to make work with Minetyst at first, but when I went to test the thing, I found an oddity. The singular tool created by this module, when run through libtools, could not be placed as a node! It seems that while I was away, screwdriver undertook a major upgrade. Instead of cycling through four different tools, each with a different capability, all the functionality has been stuffed into two distinct actions. A single screwdriver tool implements one of these functions upon left clicking (normally used for digging) and the other upon right clicking (normally used for placing nodes). Because the right click function was tied up, the tool could not be placed normally. It's not the cleanest workaround, but I've modified the screwdriver to allow itself to be placed if the player is holding the shift key when attempting to place it.

In the process, I ended up completing my libtools module. Now, the attached_node group is implemented, and tools no longer float in mid air when the node they are resting on is removed. The catch is that I had to override one of the built-in functions with a slightly-modified version of itself. The reason I don't like doing this is that if this function is changed in the main engine at some point, I may not notice right away and continue using the copy of the old code now present in my module. It's not clean, but for now, it's the best I can come up with.

Third, I built a new module called debug and modified every module to have a soft dependency on it. For now, all it does is enforce that all modules that load after it create, at most, a single global variable, and this global variable must have a very specific name based on the name of the module that defines it. I think it also throws errors if you try to access undefined variables, but I have yet to test this. Even if it works, I may remove it later. The intent is to include any debugging code here that helps make sure the rest of my code is as error-free as possible. In theory, once code is written to function with the debug module, removing the debug module will have no effect.

Yesterday, a coworker of mine set up a joke for the rest of us. Our new refrigerator has a label that says "IB Imperial Brown". Guessing by the fact that this label inhabited a hole in the protective plastic before the plastic was fully removed, I thing the hole was torn to add the label. The label therefor may not be the brand of the refrigerator, but instead, the company that installed it. Anyway, this coworker taped a printout of a sketch of Doc Brown from Back To The Future and covered the word "Imperial" with the word "Doc". It now reads "IB Doc Brown" (said out loud as "I be Doc Brown", as if he is introducing himself using bad grammar). Hoping to have my mobile on hand next time I run into the guy, I bought 80s Ep (MAGProm), as it contains a cover of (one of?) the cover song(s?) from the same movie. I won't watch the movie again, as I have left proprietary media behind, but Professor Shyguy's cover is under CC BY-SA 3.0, so I don't mind keeping it with me and playing it.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

I'm falling for it again: creating a PayPal account will bring nothing but trouble

Day 00125: Friday, 2015 July 10

PayPal got back to me today, saying that if I had a PayPal business account, I could set the account up in the name of my website, and that name would be used when processing payments. Having a PayPal account was an insufferable experience last time, but if it goes as poorly this tame as it did last time, at least I am better equipped to deal with it now. Previously, I had a singular main email address, and when PayPal locked it to my account, I didn't have a reasonable way to make accountless payments through them to merchants that don't offer a second payment option, such as Bandcamp. Now that I have more email addresses than I will ever use and now that I know that PayPal is an irritating pain in the neck to deal with, all I need to do is use a different email address from my main PayPal email address that I use for accountless payments. I still do not like the idea of sending PayPal any extra information about myself, as I will no doubt have to do if I register an account, but on the flip side, being an account holder may cause them to not write me off as badly, especially if I comply with their nosey demands. It's unlikely, but perhaps I can hassle them to the point where they actually fix their bloody system.

However, this will not be happening today. The business account registration form asks for two things I don't have: a legal business name and a business telephone number. I don't have a telephone number at all, and legally speaking, I don't have a business and therefor don't have a legal business name. I have written explaining both issues, so we'll see what comes of it.

I've been dropping by the Devote 30 store every so often, trying to get ahold of the guy that told me that he might be able to sell me a Red Pocket Mobile tablet plan. He said that he would shoot me an email once he found out for sure if he could, but that email never came. I tried talking to another representative there, but he didn't seem to be in the loop about it. Today, I caught the guy I wanted to talk to and asked him about it. He said he could do it, but he cannot keep the SIM cards in stock. Unlike the smartphone SIM cards, he has to order them as requested. As an experiment, I said I wanted to buy the plan. I know the plan is no longer available, but I wanted to see what the system would say on their end. Instead of punching it into his computer as I thought he would, he placed the order over the telephone, and it seemed to go through successfully. I suppose now I wait and see what happens. He said he would send me an email when it came in, but that didn't happen last time. I will probably drop by in a week's time and check in person.

I've decided that in order to make eating out easier for myself, I'm going to research the foods offered at local restaurants and make a list of edible and non-edible menu items. I'll start with fast food joints, as I eat more fast food than I do food at fancier restaurants. You would think that a listing of options at restaurants from PETA would be vegan, but their list admits including dairy items. While I disagree with PETA's motives, the work they put into achieving their goal is often useful to any vegan, no mater what reason said vegan may have. The lists at Munchyy Menus seem to be more accurate if you browse the vegan section, but they don't include some of my local restaurants. My lists won't be complete either, as they will really only contain restaurants that are relevant to me. I'm not sure a complete list is out there. Besides, making my own lists will allow me the chance to look over the ingredients and make decisions myself. The list at Vegan Peace should be valuable for figuring out which ingredients are vegan and not.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Country fair

Day 00127: Sunday, 2015 July 12

Today, I went to the country fair with my sister. A friend of my mother is on the city council of a local city, so she receives a pair of tickets for the fair each year. The fair isn't really her cup of tea though, so she offered the tickets to us.

This is the first time we've been to the country fair, and the theme this time appeared to be dragons. There were all sorts of dragon- and non-dragon-themed art pieces set about, including a large, spinable globe with a surface made up of triangles. In many places, there were banners that read "yes yes yes", though I'm not sure what was meant by that.

Many of the booths had beautiful hand-painted signs and many types of artwork were on display and for sale. Pottery, woodcarving, and glasswork were quite popular. Musical instruments were also available, most of them ornately-carved. Some of the pieces that stood out to me were clay sculptures made to look like human hearts and broken-off branches carved into faces.

About half-way through our time at the fair, my sister and I stopped for lunch at a vegan food stand, a place selling tofu burritos. The burritos contained quinoa, which I had not yet had a chance to try. It seems to be a fairly-bland gain, similar to rice, but with a different shape and texture. In addition to the burritos, we got delicious hibiscus drinks containing mint, oranges, and a few other plants that I do not recall.

We found a section of the fair labeled "Energy Park", where the focus was on sustainable living. Not everything there related to energy though. There were a few anti-GMO booths and a seed exchange. We hadn't known what to expect at the fair and didn't bring any seeds to exchange (not that we had any seeds to exchange anyway as we don't farm or garden). Some people from one of the universities had brought some energy demonstrations, including a music transmitter that sent music to the speaker in a beam of light. If the beam was cut off, the speaker no longer played, and if the light was sent through a filter, the music became muffled. They also had a few types of light bulbs on display with a reader that told how much energy was being drawn by each. The most efficient of these bulbs was a large LED the size and shape of a regular light bulb. Though expensive, these bulbs are supposed to last a long time and save a lot of energy, which should result in an overall savings. We also saw (and got to try) orange watermelons. They taste the same as the commonly-seen red watermelons, but for some reason, you don't see them as often. Many edible plants are this way: several colors exist, but for some reason, only one color is commonly found in markets.

At one point, we saw a cool flag that looked like a hybrid between a gay pride flag and a United States flag. The blue starry corner from the United States flag was present, but the thirteen red and white stripes had been replaced by the six rainbow stripes of the gay pride flag.

As time was running out, we came across a stand giving out Peace Chains in exchange for an optional donation. They came in a variety of languages, though I didn't see any in the language I wanted on in: Esperanto. It wouldn't have bothered me too much, but there were chains in the bogus languages of Elfish and Klingon. Why would these fantasy languages be acknowledged but not the actually-used international language of Esperanto? Admittedly, I was slightly-annoyed, and was going to leave without one. However, I decided to show that there was interest in Esperanto by asking if he had any in it, thinking that maybe if enough people asked about them, he would make them in the future. It's a good thing I asked because it turned out he already had some Esperanto chains, but I had overlooked them. I was quite relieved. I don't mind fantasy languages being used, honestly. I just think that acknowledging fantasy languages while not acknowledging an important real-world language is an insult to said real-world language. I got an Esperanto chain, my sister got a German one, and not knowing which language out mother would want one in, we brought her home both an English one and a Spanish one, all paid in full.

We over-stayed our welcome, as did many other people. After about an hour after we were all supposed to be gone, a member of the staff caught us in a sweep he was doing of the park and escorted us to the exit. Though he said we were supposed to leave through the public exit, he decided the staff exit would be a better option because it was closer. He led us out saying that there was a way back in, and that people had snuck back in before, but that he couldn't tell us how to get back in for obvious reasons. We hadn't even considered trying to sneak back in, and found it odd that he had brought up the possibility. After parting ways with him, we headed home.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

PayPal is being over-controlling as usual

Day 00129: Tuesday, 2015 July 14

Today was mainly a day of catchup. After returning home from work, I sat down and wrote up my weblog entries for the past three days without any notes. I worked from memory and wrote what happened as best I could recall.

It appears that PayPal is being a pain in the rear as usual. They said that unless I have a registered business, and therefor a legal business name, I cannot register a PayPal business account. However, they had been the ones to suggest the business account to me in the first place. Additionally, it seems that the business name, not the website, would be used as the name of the donor. This is not at all what I asked how to do. There's no reason that I shouldn't be able to donate under whatever name I choose. PayPal is just being over-controlling as usual.

I became vegan not long before I got this site up and running, so I haven't been vegan very long. At first, everything was so much better. Emotionally and physically, I felt better than I ever had. However, my muscles are now showing signs of weakness and it's scaring me a bit. I read somewhere that going vegan would eventually lead to muscle loss unless you do it right, though I didn't look into what needed to be done right away as the article was discussing what needed to be added to one's diet to get one's muscles back, meaning that it wasn't a permanent loss and could be reversed. The article mentioned "building vegan muscle", so I tried searching the Web for "vegan muscle". Nothing about my current situation turned up. The only information I could find was on body-building websites. They said that us "plat-based eaters" needed plat-based protein shakes and that diet is more important than exercise for building muscle. The protein shake recipe I saw included protein powder, but all the protein powder I could see at the market was expensive and all the labels I checked said the products contained were milk-based. I am hoping that a lack of protein is the only problem. I will try to get more protein in my diet, though protein shakes are not an option at the moment.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

I feel sick

Day 00130: Wednesday, 2015 July 15

Today's events have become muddled in my head due to heavy vibrations scrambling my brain near the end of the day. Expect inaccuracies and a lack of completeness in today's weblog entry.

My mother bought tickets to a country fair, though not the one I went to a few days ago, for her mother and her brother. From what I gather, they both agreed to go. The tickets included seats at a musical performance that would be held at the fair by a band the two enjoy. However, both backed out at the last minute, so with the tickets already paid for, my mother invited me to go with her instead.

On the way to the fair, we received word that my mother's brother had ended up having to go to the emergency room for his ongoing health issues. We decided to try to sell our tickets and go to see him in the hospital. After looking into the tickets further, we realized that they would not be easy to sell; it seems that the tickets without performance seats cost next to nothing and that without seats, you still get to hear the performance. After my mother's brother contacted us letting us know that he was doing better and was likely to be released soon, we decided not to waste the tickets and headed to the fair.

The first stand we went to was about safety and preparedness. The community emergency response team there were offering inexpensive courses on being prepared for disaster, available on four different days, though being a non-driver, the reaching the location of the courses would be a challenge. At some point, if I have time, I should look into how to get prepared online.

We passed by a stand claiming to tell you whether or not you are going to heaven based on the answers to two questions. No doubt the questions were something such as Do you accept Jesus Christ as your lord and savior? and Have you repented for your sins?. I don't even believe in a heaven to go to though, so I guess my soul, if I even have one, is probably lost.

We stopped by a stand mostly-selling hair accessories, but at least some of them were made from leather, making them unappealing. They also carried metal signs with amusing phrases such as BEWARE OF WELL... JUST BEWARE.

Next in our path was the food court, but not much appeared to be edible. The only item that looked vegan was the snow cones.

After that, we visited some livestock that were penned-up in a large building. The treatment of these creatures was mildly-disturbing. Don't get me wrong, I'm no non-human animal lover, but once you no longer use animal products, things change a bit in your head. As an animal product user, you say to yourself that what is done is necessary. It may be bad, but there is no other way. But as a vegan seeing it, there was no real way to write it off. The pigs were shaved, which wasn't too bad, aside from the fact that there were razor cuts all over the pigs' skin. If you're going to shave the pigs', could you at least avoid injuring them? The milk cows were incredibly bony. One's bones were sticking so far out of its body that it looked worse than one of those pictures they show you of starving people. Her utter was huge and vainy. It couldn't have been easy for her to stand under the weight with so little muscle on her body. The sheep and goats appeared to be doing relatively-okay, though some of the goats were being dragged through an obstacle course unwillingly. I suppose the obstacle course was harmless, but it also seemed pointless. Before leaving, we watched a group of steers get judged for fitness for market. It sounded like they were awarding them ribbons but had plans to slaughter them later.

We found a storytelling blacksmith shop, but had missed the first show. We decided to catch the second show, which would occur later.

Next came a large building full of cadged animals, though these ones seemed to be treated a lot better than the ones in the last building. They all looked healthy as far as I could tell and didn't seem upset. Some slept, some watched people looking at them, and some mostly ignored us. Rabbits and chickens of various breeds were the most common, but we also saw a lioness in a larger cage. She paced back and forth, seemingly wanting to get to the pair of turkeys that were being loud on the other side of the room. She is a predator, after all. After a while, her handler came to the edge of the page, and the lioness ran over and started rubbing against the cadge and the handler affectionately like a large hose cat. It was pretty clear that the lioness loved this woman and did not feel like she was being treated abusively. A sign on the cadge explained that this species of lion had formerly been believed to be extinct. They had been hunted to nonexistence in the wild, but some still lived on in "private collections". Now, a program had been set up to try to breed them back out of the brink of extinction. Having so few specimens, I worry about inbreeding, but maybe lions don't have that issue. If I understand correctly, lion prides are composed of individuals all stemming from a single father. Only one male is allowed to breed with all the females when in the wild, until that male's position is usurped. But as the new male is a part of the pride, he is related to the father, and therefore related to all the females. Inbreeding might not be an issue for them.

We went to the final area of the fair (save for the concert stage), a large building full of booths. Due to my brain getting scrambled later, I don't recall much that was there. One product that stood out though came from an anti-aging booth. This product supposedly prevents and reverses aging of the mind! I don't have the money to drop at the moment, but as I get older, it would be nice to not lose my mind. There was also a cable service provider that was trying to get my mother to switch our service over from our current provider. I wouldn't mind a switch, actually, as our current provider is one of the most evil cable providers here in the states. If we do switch, I may lose the website, as the new provider may not allow hosting of servers from home, but it would be worth it to keep a bit of money out of the pockets of Comcast. If the site goes down in the next week, it's probably because we switched over.

Noticing the time, we found we were late to see the blacksmith storytelling show. We rushed out and caught the end of it, but we missed almost the whole thing. My mother has thought about setting a timer and I had thought about setting a calendar event with an alert, but neither of us followed through and it cost us. Next time, I will set a calendar alert if trying to catch something of interest.

We went back to the booth building, but again, I don't recall much of what was there. I did get beckoned over by someone calling themselves a Gideon, a member of a group I've never heard of. It turns out they are the people giving out all (or many of?) the tiny pocket bibles and have a goal of teaching people how to become Christian. Apparently, I look like the godless heathen that I am, and he wanted to save me.

Lastly, we went out to the stage to see the show for which we had tickets. The speakers were way too loud. At first, it was bearable if I stuffed my earlobes into my ears, but that only lasted so long. It got worse and worse until I had to leave. I considered sitting through it anyway, but the fact is that the heavy vibrations were making me sick. I had a headache and nausea, and I had stayed longer than I should have. It turns out my mother had wanted to ask if I wanted to leave, but there was just no space between most of the loud songs in which to speak. She too was feeling the effects, though not as badly as I, and wanted to leave. My plan had been to move outside the chaired area to a spot way in the back where it might be bearable, but she instead wanted to take refuge in the booth building. It turns out that was the better choice. Once in the building, we could still hear the heavy booming of the band's base! I remained sick the rest of our stay, though I could hear perfectly fine once we got into the building. On the other hand, my mother seemed fine aside from the fact that she couldn't hear well for quite a while. After browsing the booths a bit more, we returned home.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

PayPal is a pain in the rear to use

Day 00131: Thursday, 2015 July 16

PayPal wrote back saying that I cannot create an account on behalf of my website, but I can create a business account on behalf of an individual. Heading back to their registration form to take another look, I noticed something that I'm pretty sure was not there before: text stating that if there was no legal business name, to enter something that best represents what I'm doing. PayPal likes to send a different version of their forms based on what country they think you are in, so it should come at no surprise that information will appear and disappear each time you see the page if you are using Tor as you should.

The registration form claims to require the use of numbers or non-alphanumeric characters in your password, however, every password I tried that had non-alphanumeric characters caused the form to have an unspecified error, without even any hint that the problem was the password. I assume that because the PayPal form isn't able to take some characters in password, that they do not store their passwords securely. If they were properly hashing their passwords, it wouldn't matter what characters I was using in it.

Next, PayPal demanded the last four digits of my Social Security number, which I reluctantly handed over. When this goes south, it will not be fun. However, this form page threw an unspecified error as well. The only things on that page of the form were my Social Security ending and my data of birth, both of which were entered correctly. Once again, I have pestered PayPal about the issue.

Josh Woodward has a new song out: Do Not Go Gentle. It's a pretty song, but a bit slow. It's the sort of song I would enjoy more if I were trying to relax right now, but I'm very awake and getting things done.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Tablet plan shopping

Day 00132: Friday, 2015 July 17

My mobile has been out of service for a few days, so I thought now would be a good time to shop around again.

First, I stopped by the Devote 30 store once more. Luckily for me, the correct representative was in, so I was able to get right to business. He hadn't heard about the SIM card coming in, so he called someone to check on it. It appears that Devote 30 is unable to get or activate these SIM cards either, which isn't too surprising. I had to cancel the order, but not before the representative tried to talk me into switching the order to a SIM card for a different company that would give me two gigabytes of data per month for $25 USD. If I wanted two gigabytes of data per month, I could get Straight Talk's four gigabyte/two month plan for $40 USD and save five dollars each month over the plan Devote 30 offered me.

While I was in the area, I stopped at the MetroPCS store to see if they had opened up their tablet plans to bring-your-own device customers yet. This isn't the location I would normally go to, but I figured I was already here and I could ask at both locations in hopes that they would both express to their superiors that a potential customer wanted this. It turns out that one of the people at this location has already been pestering his superiors about this, and says he'll continue doing so in hopes that he won't have to turn me away again next month.

Next, I stopped by the MetroPCS location that I normally drop in at, but I found that they have closed shop! It's a good thing I stopped at the other one, because this one won't be selling me anything any time soon. Having exhausted my options as I knew I likely would, I picked up a scratch card to renew my Straight Talk service. After using it a while, it certainly shows that it is bargain brand service, but for the price, I can't really complain too much. The only better deal I know of doesn't really work due to being exclusive to one device that doesn't meet my needs.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Minetyst work continues

Day 00134: Sunday, 2015 July 19

Most of my time today was spent carving up minetest_game's default module to create Minetyst's default module. I thought I had finished with default, and Minetyst is in a fairly usable state right now, so I uploaded the current version to the server and moved the spawn point in order to generate a new area that both looks better than the old spawn area and is closer to what Minetyst will really look like. While I was at work though, I got a few new ideas about how default should look in order to make it look more glitchy (default in Minetyst is designed to create rare glitch-looking biomes) and more thought out. The new ideas won't effect map generation though, so there's no need to work on this further tonight.

After thinking that I had finished default, I spent a little bit of time planning the entrance for the massive tunnel that will be my main project in-game. In my last world, I had a pretty decent tunnel entrance, at least from a security standpoint. While I want my tunnel to be public, the fact is, other people can mess it up in various ways. My last tunnel was liquidproof, and with the kind of node protection I had at the time, fireproof. However, it wasn't really gravelproof.Someone could clog up the tunnel entrance by dropping sand or gravel from a higher area. Today, I developed a couple of new entrance strategies that, at least right now, appear to be completely protected. The first is implemented by placing four sideways stairs at the top of the tunnel in such a way that they form a one node wide hole, but off-center from where sand and gravel can fall. This keeps everything aside from players out, but has the nasty side effect that a player can only enter the tunnel, never exit due to gravity. The second method is better, and is what I plan to use. It involves placing four slabs turned sideways on the side of the tunnel, which would then protrude from the ground. The sideways slabs form a doorway wide enough for the players to fit through, but due to being off-center and the way liquid mechanics are implemented in Minetest, liquid cannot get through. Falling nodes such as sand and gravel also can't get through due to the doorway being on the side and not the top, and nothing flammable is anywhere in site to be burned. One disadvantage to both these methods is that they require use of a screwdriver to set up. Screwdrivers are made from steel and are worn with each use, and if you know me, you know that my main goal in Minetest is to hoard as much iron as I can find. I think the sacrifice is worth it for a decent tunnel entrance though, especially because I'm working on implementing a way to make iron (as well as every other node) renewable.

After settling on an entrance style, I began building a model of how the upper sections of my tunnel would look to see how feasible it would be to use that entryway style. It seems to work well, I just need to put a small balcony-like structure just inside the doorway leading to the stairs.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Ssh scare and returned strength

Day 00136: Tuesday, 2015 July 21

I tried to log into my Minetest server this morning to make sure the thing is still running. I've been having it go down on me lately due to small errors in my code. Once one of these bugs shuts down the server, I just have to read the debug file to find the error and correct it. Sure enough, the server was down. I tried to ssh into the server, but my client was acting as if it had never seen the server before; it showed be the server's RSA fingerprint (a value I should have copied down somewhere but did not) and asked if I wanted to connect. I checked my DNS records to be sure my client was connecting to the right host, and sure enough, the record is pointed to 10.0.0.1, the correct address on my local network. I accepted (and copied down) the key, but the server will not accept my password. No other machine on my local network should be running a ssh server, so I don't know what is going on. If the local IP addresses got jumbled, I should be hitting an error message about the server not accepting connections on that port. For that matter, my site should not be accessible any more, as the port forwarding still points to the original IP address, but the site is still up.

*UPDATE*: I found the issue, it was a typographical error in the server name. I was trying to access chicken.hn.y.sh, one letter off from my server name of chicken.hn.y.st. For anyone curious about the name of my server, I named it chicken because it runs headless. Until recently, I didn't think about how morbid of a pun that is. It's not a name I would use these days, but I also don't feel like renaming the server until it is replaced.

After fixing the bug and restarting the server, I went back to my private world to work on planning out both my decoy home and my spawn room/future tunnel entrance. The tunnel entrance went well, thoug I found an error in my initial planning of it. After fixing the problem (which prevented people from leaving the spawn room), everything seemed in order.

I thought I had finished planning my decoy abode before. It is basically just a dungeon near the spawn area that I was going to repair by filling in the broken spots with glass. The upper room is cut in two by a large underground canyon and looks quite nice once the missing walls, floor, and ceiling are filled in with glass. The lower area is completely trashed by the nearby caves (which are actually the lover part of the canyon that slices through the room above). In fact, out of confusion as to how even to repair it, I decided to take a look and see what the dungeon looked like with cave generation turned off. The dungeon looked completely different! The presence of the caves is quite literally interfering with the generation process of the chambers and hallways. Based on past experiences and accidents when dealing with the map generator, I think the air in the caves is being read as air from within the dungeon, as they are exactly the same node. Anyway, I've been calling my upper room the Glass Room, and I had a new idea regarding it. People often ask me and ask each other if they can take up residence in my home or the homes of others.I don't want to damage the surrounding area myself, but I don't mind if other people do. The canyon that cuts through the Glass Room offers an opportunity to build my own hallways that lead outside of what will be my protected space. If someone wants to join me, they can build their own rooms beyond this point. I managed to get two hallways added to the Glass Room leading in perpendicular directions. Going back the the mangled mess below, I managed to put two hallways in perpendicular directions there too. The catch is that I had to curve the paths downward to make them even get barely into a separate protectable area from the potential rooms above. If someone chooses a lower area and then builds upward, they will take away the possibility of one of the upper opportunities getting used. Second, there wasn't much space to work down in the lower area. One path would be perfect if my protected space extended just one node further, but it does not. The second looks outright bad, utilizing a combination of downward curving, lack of stairs, and sand/gravel nodes embedded in the floor and walls. The only remedy would be for me to close that area off to expansion. Neither of these paths do well with glass walls in combination with expansions, so I swapped the glass walls for stone brick walls. I think I will do the same for the halls leading off of the Glass Room, though it would be a shame to take away the beautiful sight from within the room itself. I think I will leave the Glass Room repaired using glass.

I've not wanted to get up and do much due to lack of sleep, but tonight at work, I got a chance to put my muscles to the test. I'm either stronger than I was or (more likely) I am stronger than I remember. Adding more protein to my diet has caused me to regain my lost strength. I'm glad that scary ordeal is over. Though on the down side, I've sort of gotten sick of the vegan patties I originally used for protein in the past. I think part of why I wasn't getting enough protein is because I was tired of eating those. The funny thing is that I don't usually get tired of foods. I either like something no matter how much I get or I don't like it at all. Furthermore, I liked the flavor of those patties better than the flavor of meat. I found some protein bars to fill the holes left by dropping those patties though, and I will eat the last of the ones I still have tomorrow at work.

I don't expect to get much done tomorrow as I have a thirteen hour shift at work.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Major remodeling, both on the site and in Minetyst

Day 00137: Wednesday, 2015 July 22

I was finding myself doubting the need for a fork of minetest_game again. After all, couldn't I do a lot of what I want by just adding extra modules? I was thinking that maybe I should hold off on building a new game until I had enough modules to create a game out of them. At that point, I could simply remove minetyst_game from my server entirely and fill in a gap or two still left by its absence with new modules for the occasion. However, minetest_game simply doesn't meet my needs. It's a survival-type subgame and I want a subgame more geared toward construction. Furthermore, on a technical level, minetest_game aliases some engine-related nodes to other engine-related nodes. There's nothing inherently wrong with that (aside from the fact that many of those nodes should be consolidated to use just one name in the engine), and in fact I do it with one node in my subgame, but once it's done, there is no going back with the old map. Once a map has had two nodes treated as one for a while, it causes changes that are not reversible. Furthermore, would there ever be a time when my modules could truly separate from minetest_game without a forking of some sort? I can draw somewhat, but I'll probably never be able to replace the minetest_game sound effects. As a free software user, I have the freedom to fork the software I use, and if it makes me happy and is not disrupting others, I should do so.

Speaking of my minetest_game fork, I need to get going on learning Esperanto. I want my node names to be written in that language, so the sooner I can figure out what those node names are the better. In Minetest, once you have named a node, you pretty much have three choices. You could leave the name as it is. In that case, if I had already added English-named nodes, I would have a part English part Esperanto game, and that seems like a mess. You could change the name and make an alias. If you do that, you need to leave the alias in the code pretty much forever, as the game does not change all the names on the map automatically. Rather, it changes the names on the map only in places that get loaded into memory at the time they are loaded. Any section of the map that does not get loaded will retain the old names and still need the alias for when those nodes finally do get visited by players. If I did this, I would have English embedded in my Esperanto game, and I don't really want that. The last option is to rename the nodes without creating aliases. This causes any node on the map that still uses the old name to become an "unknown node", a gray and pink ugly node that isn't really good for much, save to act as a place holder in case the node definition is ever restored. Seeing as I would be changing an all-English game to an all-Esperanto game, all nodes besides the built-in air would become unknown, ruining everyone's creations. This seems like the worst option of all.

I had been leaving the module names intact for modules that I didn't make many changes to from minetest_game's version, but that might not be the best idea. If another module depends on a module that I forked, it may think it has what it needs if my module is present when it really does not. I think renaming all the modules would be a better idea, and as a bonus, that would allow me to likewise convert those names to Esperanto. I also have been thinking about how messed up my version of the default module is. It's really gimmicky, and guests on my server deserve better.

I decided that maybe I should just remove default from the game entirely and just treat the node names used by the engine that are within the default namespace as aliases like the regular map generator aliases. That would free me to pretty much do whatever I want with those nodes. Originally, I was planning to do something very simple with default. I had planned to make a very few of those nodes spawn during map generation very rarely. These would be the nodes such as saplings, water, and lava that are involved in their own replication. From there, I would find a way to generate all the other default nodes using those nodes. I think I should go back to that plan, but call the module whatever the Esperanto word for "antiques" is. This time though, the antiques module won't be self-sustaining. I had a very messy setup for generating and regenerating antique nodes, and I think a separate "renew" module would make things cleaner gameplay-wise. I could for example set up a water filtration node that when placed next to water nodes will occasionally generate a dirt or sand node that it has "filtered out of the water".

Last time I had a Minetest server, I tried to build a very long tunnel to a very specific point. However, people kept putting in requests that I connect my tunnel to their creations, most of which lied in completely-different directions. I never made it to where I wanted to go because I was swamped with requests to tunnel to other places. This time, things will be different. I have learned from my mistakes and am now better-organized. In order to get me to accept a tunnel request, you must go through one of two channels. The first option is to pay me with a chest full of a particular node my subgame will have, a node formed by crafting together nine steel blocks. That is the equivalent of 2592 iron ingots. Even if people are willing to pay (they won't be), gathering up that much iron for me will slow down the requests significantly, allowing me to actually make progress in the direction I want to go. The second option is to convince me that you can type in fluent Esperanto. This will allow you to request gratis tunnel entrances, but would in theory mean that once someone learns Esperanto, they could singlehandedly fill my tunnel entrance queue. For that reason, if you choose to take the Esperanto option instead of paying me, there will be sever limitations on where I will tunnel to. The main tunnel has twelve major veins, so in order to request a tunnel entrance without paying, the nearest planned vein must be completed up to the point that it would need to branch off to reach your requested area. That pretty much means that for the first year or so, gratis tunnel entrances will only be available in one direction from the spawn area.

I know I've been doing a lot of speaking about Esperanto today, but it's been on my mind lately. I have just a little bit more to say before I put away my virtual pen. I plan to begin writing my weblog in Esperanto in an effort to help myself learn the language (I will translate all entries to English for any English-readers). Once I know the language well enough, I'll go back and translate the rest of the website, including past weblog entries. I'll move the current English things I've written to /en/ and put the new Esperanto work in /eo/. Anything that doesn't need multiple versions such as licenses, CSS, and non-text work will remain outside the language code directories. I'll set up redirects to deal with old URIs that may still be in circulation. for now, the redirects will point to the English versions of pages, as they are the only pages in existence, but once the Esperanto versions are available, they will become the canonical versions of the pages and the redirects will shift to point to those. If you have any bookmarks/hyperlinks and are only interested in the English version, update your bookmarks/hyperlinks accordingly.

I fixed the issue with March 21's weblog entry, or at least I fixed it enough to get that entry added back to the site. The PHP work is probably done, but there is some CSS work that still needs doing. Now that the entry is back up though, it has fallen significantly on my priority list and I'll likely not finish it for a long while.

*Update*: It appears the Web server is not cooperating with me. If "{filename}.xhtml" is missing, Apache is more than happy to serve "{filename}.xhtml.asc" in its place. This has been more of a nuisance than a help up until today. But now, when I tried to put that to use by creating "{filename}.xhtml.php" files to do some redirecting, I find that Apache refuses to serve the PHP replacement pages. Due to how minimal my site is, that was my only real option for redirecting. Instead, I'm going to have to put up ugly pages saying that the page has been moved and offering a hyperlink to the new locations. It's not great, but it's the best I have right now.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

I had to cut my Peace Chain

Day 00138: Thursday, 2015 July 23

I think I'm going to scrap all work on Minetyst *again*. This will probably be at least the fifth time I have done so, if you include all the times before Minetyst was called Minetyst. I think forking minetest_game just isn't the best idea for what I want to accomplish. It would save me a lot of time in some areas, but it is costing me a lot of time in others and just isn't getting me where I want to be anyway. I'll take the sound files from minetest_game just because they would be difficult for me to replace and because I don't think they are as likely as the images to get players to try talking me into "updating Minetest" thinking that my game is just minetest_game with added modules. Starting completely over as opposed to forking also allows me to start Minetyst as a small, manageable project and expand it as time allows. The way I see it, I'll only need six fairly small modules to start with: a debug module (used to enforce some basic coding standards during development), a stair library module (used to make defining stair nodes easy), the main module that defines basic nodes needed by the engine and little else (will require the stair library as the engine requires two types of stair node), a tool node library (defining nodes that function as tools *and* nodes is a pain without this library), a module that adds a few basic tools (using the tool library), and a module to add basic protection against vandalism. None of this should be overly hard to produce. With these, I could set up a very simple server and let the game evolve as it will.

Unfortunately, I have given up on finding a reasonable Git host. Because the Minetest Forums allow linking to GitHub accounts in user profiles but not any other Git host accounts, and because I need my code to be available to my users, I will be putting my Minetyst-related work on GitHub once the main server goes live. If I find a reasonable Git host later, I'll simply move my work to the new host.

The string of my Peace Chain became tangled around my neck and I couldn't get it off. I ended up having to cut it. Until I can find a new string somewhere, I'll have to put that away. Actually, come to think of it, we have extra strings lying around at work that we just throw away. I'll pick up one of those next time I get the chance.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Moving to Coos Bay

Day 00139: Friday, 2015 July 24

I decided to try setting up a new credit union account for a number of reasons. For one, that means I'll have more places to withdraw money from if I'm out and about. For another, if something bad happens, all my berries aren't in one basket. But I think most of all, I wanted to do it as an experiment. When I opened my last account, I was a very different person with a very different set of beliefs. I wanted to know what it was like from my current perspective.

When setting up an account, as expected, the representative requested a telephone number. I said I didn't have one, and she had to go talk to her boss. It seems that her boss told her to use my work telephone number, which is not a private line and I cannot be reached by it. She looked up my employer's number on the Web because I had said I would need to run across the street to pick the number up, and when she went to enter it, she saw I had a previous number according to the government. She asked me to verify it, so I gave her the last number I had used at my old credit union. It turns out that number wasn't a match. She read the number back to me and I think it might have been a number I had *only* given to my employer. My employer ratted me out to the government! Be careful what you tell your employer, they are probably required by law to act as spies and report employee information to the government. I should know this already, but seeing it in action here was a real wake up call and would have made the whole experience worth while, had it not been actually worthwhile already for the right reasons.

This new credit union, First Tech Federal Credit Union seems to offer their services across the country, but unless you are a resident of my county, you must be employed by a major tech company to gain membership. How odd is that? They also claim to have the best security available compared to other credit unions, but I saw that the teller was using a Windows-based machine. They may be more secure than other credit unions as they claim, I wouldn't know, but they clearly are not doing everything they can to be secure. If they were, they wouldn't be using that security hole of an operating system.

The credit union has a partially-self-help coin counter set up, though they charge a five percent fee for use by non-members. You pour your coins in on your own, but you have to take the receipt to a representative to actually get your money. Still, it's better than the setup at my other credit union where they take the coins to the back. Admittedly, it's not a huge improvement, but it does make me feel less bad as I don't have to hand the representative a huge pile of coins.

One complaint I have though is their interest rate policy. In order to qualify for their higher interest rate on a checking account, you must spend from your debit card (which is required by them to have your legal name on it so merchants will know who you are) twelve times each month, have a direct deposit or automatic payment from the account once per month, and be registered for electronic statements. The electronic statements are a good thing, but the rest of that is utter rubbish. My employer doesn't offer direct deposit, so I would have to set up an automatic payment. That would mean trusting a company with authorization to automatically take my money, which would require actually trusting a company. I shouldn't have to trust other companies. As for the debit card purchases, that makes it way to easy to track me. The credit union would know where and how much I spend, the merchant would have my legal name, and the merchant would have a card number with which to chain my purchases together with. That is not okay. I could get a savings account instead, but I was told that a savings account has the same interest rate as the checking account without meeting the requirements does. Looking back over the notes the representative gave me, there is a second type savings account though that has double the interest rate, though it doesn't have as high of an interest rate as the checking account would if I jumped through their noxious requirements.

When I got home, my Internet connection was down, so I couldn't set up electronic statements. The representative had told me that she couldn't set it up, I had to do it through the website. Once the connection came back up, I didn't get on it right away, and the credit union's physical location closed for the night. The website wanted to argue with me about email address formats even though I gave it a valid email address, then when I found one it liked, it told me that it didn't match the one on file. I tried giving the site the same email address that I gave the branch representative, but it said that one wasn't the one on file either. It's also worth noting that the website loads incredibly slowly, and that's when it decides to load at all.

I did a little work on Minetyst's images, setting up dummy nodes to test the images as I went. When adding descriptions to the dummy nodes, I found that Minetest doesn't handle Unicode strings properly. I can't provide the correct mouseover text for many of the nodes.

It appears that Paramat was the one that limited biome generation to only function on the surface and above, and it may have been a conscious decision, potentially in an effort to speed map generation. When I had wanted to create true retro biomes (before this site went up), it was that limitation that stopped me, as ores needed to generate deeper but couldn't due to the retro stone nodes not spawning deeply enough for contain the ore nodes. However, it seems Paramat has now removed that limitation! Though I no longer have that specific idea in mind, this could be very useful for keeping ugly biome cutoff lines away in other biomes.

My mother nailed an interview she had today, so we're packing up the family and moving out to Coos Bay at the end of August. A change of scenery will be nice, and I can finally quit waiting to look for a new job. The problem has been that she has been looking for a job and if she got one out of the area, I would have to leave my own new job if I got one. It wouldn't look good for me to hold a job only for a month or two, so I had to wait until the beginning of the school year, as she she is a school teacher and would know if she had gotten a job by then. Now I can leave my awful job in peace and attempt to get a new job in about a month, once we've moved. As a side note, this may be the end of this website for the time being. I have no idea if a server will be able to be set up at the new location with the new ISP. Then again, it could work out just fine and the site might stay up. With or without the website, I'm hopeful for the future.

On tomorrow's agenda is heading back to the credit union to get the email address issue looked into, get the money switched over to the savings account with higher interest, and ask if they have a branch in Coos Bay. If they do not, I can scratch the first two items off the agenda and close the account.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Tutanota premium accounts are now available

Day 00141: Sunday, 2015 July 26

I found information on how to set um my keyboard to type Esperanto Characters. The good news is that it works and I can now type all letter characters used in Esperanto with ease. The bad news is that the change borked my quote and double quote key. The key with a Windows logo had previously been useless, but it now acts as a modifier key. Holding it, I can type whichever Esperanto character I needed an accent on, and it will apply the correct one. However, the single quote key now also acts as a modifier, altering the next key I hit to have a standard accent, one not used in Esperanto. If I remember to hold the Windows key when I press the single quote key, I can override this. But now comes the stupid part. The double quote (shift + single quote) is taken up as well and need the Windows key to be pressed to override it, but pressing this three-key combination does not always work. About half the time, no character is generated when I try to type a double quote. I can seem to find a pattern to when it works and not either. It's also worth noting that the "¢" and "€" symbols are also now accessible by combining the Windows key, "e" key, and for the "¢" symbol, the shift key.

In case the page at the URI linked to above goes dead, the way to activate this functionality is to first run setxkbmap -layout "us" -variant "alt-intl" -option "lv3:lwin_switch,esperanto:qwerty" on the command line to make it take effect right away, then add it to one of the files that is run upon every log in, such as ~/.bash_aliases, to make it persist after restarting or logging out.

I worked on Minetyst a little and got a few of the images made. The most notable was the clay image. I was trying to draw desert sand but it came out horribly. The pattern was not sand-like at all, but it was almost perfect for clay. I modified the pattern a little, and messed with the colors a lot, and made the image pretty usable for use in clay nodes.

Before I had heard about Esperanto, I had wanted to learn Lojban. I don know what made Esperanto seem more appealing, but it made me switch plans. However, Lojban is still out there and I'm not really sure which is a better language. I tried to find comparisons of the two languages, but nothing about the things I care about such as lack of ambiguity. It seems both have a rigid structure that makes them very well built, syntacticly-speaking, but that's about all I could find. Learning a language is of no use though if there is no one else that uses that language though. Esperanto is a common enough language that it has it's own two-letter ISO 639‑1 language code, a status reserved for "major" languages. I decided that I would check on Lojban's status, and if it had an ISO 639‑1 language code, I would continue trying to figure out which to learn first, then probably move on to the other. However, if Lojban had not been assigned such a code, I would write it off for the time being. I only have so much time and I need to put my efforts to where they will actually be useful. As it turns out, Lojban is not common enough for such a code, so I won be learning it for now. That's not to say that Lojban isn't to say Lojban isn't a great language, only that it hasn't picked up as much momentum as Esperanto yet.

I decided to log into my Tutanota account today to delete it. I never use that email account as it's such a pain to use. Tutanota's end-to-end encryption requires special software to use, but the software has a number of limitations. First, the only option for a desktop client is Outlook Express with the Tutanota plugin. Really? The only email client that can be used is proprietary? As for the Android application, its source code is available, but the application is available only in three places: Google Play, the Amazon Store, and a webpage blocked by CloudFlare. Google and Amazon refuse to allow you to download applications except through their own proprietary software, so you can't download the Tutanota application from them without using proprietary software. As for the webpage, it's blocked by CloudFlare, so Tor users such as myself are stuck. There is simply no way to win. The final option is to use the Web interface, but that means having your Web browser constantly open to that page, which is a pain. Tutanota mail is not a feasible option in its current state.

The plan was to log in to the account and delete it using the provided form, which asks for feedback as to why you are deleting it. I would explain the situation, then come back once things at Tutanota are better fleshed out. However, it seems that two weeks ago, they sent me an email that I missed due to checking mail being a pain. It said that premium accounts are now available, and for a limited time, if you open one, you get five gigabytes of extra storage space. I wrote back and asked if the offer was still good and if catch-all addresses are offered if you bring your own domain. If the offer is still valid and catch-all addresses are offered, I'll get a premium account now while the extra storage space is being offered and wait out the issues while they get ironed out. If catch-all addresses are not implemented, Tutanota won't meet my needs and I don't need an account at my domain. The mail host used for my domain must use a catch-all address. In this case, I'll still delete my account and wait for the accessibility issues to be worked out. Once ready, I'll use a gratis Tutanota account for my secondary email address that needs to be disconnected from my domain. Finally, if the offer is no longer valid, there is no longer any rush to set up the account. I might as well not pay for the time I won't be able to fully use it, and I'll delete the account and wait for the accessibility issues to be fixed before getting the premium account.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Perfecting my keyboard setup

Day 00142: Monday, 2015 July 27

Because I can't find any communities to hang out in, I decided to join a language learning website. I can look up as many words as I like, but without seeing it in action, I'll lever pick up the correct sentence structure of Esperanto.

I found a better way to set my keyboard up for typing in Esperanto. I got a lead that said that the Linux keyboard already has shortcuts for accented characters using the compose key. I looked up how to set a compose key, and found that my keyboard now functioned the way I wanted it to! THe shortcuts mentioned didn't work, but holding the Windows key (now set as the compose key) and typing the character I wanted an accent over worked and added the correct accent for use in the Esperanto language, and the quote key was working properly again! But why? That seemed a bit too good to be true. I worried that the keyboard was currently in a hybrid state using parts from both the command I used yesterday and the command I used today. I altered the command in the ~/.bash_aliases file, then rebooted. Sure enough, my fancy new keyboard capabilities went away. After much debugging, I found that the appropriate command is setxkbmap -option lv3:lwin_switch,esperanto:qwerty. However, and here's the tricky part, the command in ~/.bash_aliases is not run on log in. Not knowing this made it very difficult to figure out what was going on. Opening the command line causes this file to be run, and oddly enough, opening Geany also causes this file to be run. Opening Mousepad does not, however. I decided to try creating a ~/.xsession file and moving everything from ~/.bash_aliases (all custom things I added and want run on startup) and appending startxfce4 to it. I didn't think that would work, but now the keyboard (and everything else) is working the way I want it to!

One of my bosses asked if I was transferring to a new work location of the same business when I move out to Coos Bay. I explained that I didn't think this was possible, as we are a franchise and as far as transferring goes, that makes us a separate business from the locations out at the coast. However, she explained that I was wrong: the owner of the local franchise also owns the locations out at Coos Bay. I thought about it, and the intelligent thing to do is to transfer instead of quitting right away. That will insure that I actually have a job when I get there, and I will have all the time I need to search for a better job. Lovely. It seems I'm stuck at the same dead-end job as before for the time being.

I got home from work very late and everyone was in bed. I don't know the full story, but it seems the kitchen faucet's handle is broken off making it impossible to get water from the sink. This should be "fun".

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

There's no "y" in Esperanto

Day 00144: Wednesday, 2015 July 29

I'm doing a bit better today, though I still feel quite unwell. I went into work only to find that my shift had thankfully been covered so I was able to head straight home.

It has come to my attention that there is no "y" in Esperanto, rendering both the "Minetyst" name and the //y.st. domain itself as fairly bad options for use with Esperanto. That said, I'm not sure this was avoidable in a positive way. The //st. registry was the only one to write me back saying that I could buy one of their short domains. No other registry (of those that I even seemed to qualify for) responded. And that's not to mention the fact that the //st. registry does not require me to give them a telephone number that I do not have, unlike every other registry I have worked with. All the vowels in the "*.st." namespace were taken, save for y, and without a vowel, anything I make with the domain would be unpronounceable. So really, //y.st. was the only logical choice.

Paramat, of the Minetest community, has been doing some major upgrading of the Minetest engine's map generator. Many new node aliases are in use, so unless I want my subgame to be stuck using an outdated version of the engine for a while after the next version is out, I had better shift focus to the unstable version of the game for now. In the upcoming version of Minetest, it seems the v5 and v7 map generators are now equal in terms of node aliases used. I had been planning on using a v5 map due to it using more of the nodes without as much intervention on my part, but now, I may go with a v7 map instead. The v7 terrain is harder to navigate, but it looks less like a fantasy landscape. The v6 map generator has received upgrades as well, but it has no custom biome support, instead just providing all the biomes on its own. It's easier to set up, but it's also less flexible, so I will continue ignoring it as a possibility for my world but make sure my subgame remains compatible with it in case others want to use my subgame with that map generator.

It appears that our the franchise owner at my job does not actually own a store location at Coos Bay, so I will need to quit and look for a new job after all.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.